LEWIS SAUNDERS

Frontend Engineer

📞 07426774243 🏻 @ lewissaunders100@gmail.com 🔗 https://lewis-saunders-portfolio.vercel.app/ 👂 Farnborough, Hampshire

SUMMARY

Experienced Front End Engineer with a strong proficiency in modern front end technologies and experience with back end technologies. Specialising in React, Next.js and TypeScript. Experienced with all Agile development methodologies such as Kanban, Scrum and Scrumban. Highly driven, motivated and quick to pick up new technologies, with a proven track record developing visible front-end services to strict deadlines.

SKILLS

Languages

JavaScript TypeScript HTML/CSS SQL PHP Ruby

Libraries/Frameworks/Other Technologies

React.js	Next.j	is My	QL Jest	st Sele	nium	Capybar	a Cucum	ber Wo	Wordpress		Tailwind	
Laravel	Frame	r Motion	RESTf	ul APIs	GraphQ	L CMS	S UX/UI	Figma	MUI	Yup	Git	
Jenkins	Jira	AWS	Docker	DevTools Po		ostman SitePrism		BrowserStack		Tizen Studio		
Android S	Studio	XCode	Redis	Launch	Darkly	PNPM	Agile De	velopment	Scru	m	Kanban	

Keycloak

STRENGTHS



Self-Starter

Consistency taking sole responsibility for tasks, bugs or potential UI improvements that I observe. I believe independent working is equally important as teamwork, and I pride myself on taking the incentive to take full ownership of my work



Supportive

I ensure that my colleagues are aware of my willingness to assist them when they needed. Whether that be unblocking their technical barriers, or being an active listener. I believe supportive team work in this way leads to better results and a stronger team moral.

EXPERIENCE

08/2024 - Present

London, United Kingdom

Frontend Engineer

Health Data Research UK

- Development and maintenance of dynamic web applications using Next.js, Typescript and Material UI, ensuring high performance, SEO optimisation, meeting accessibility standards and matching UI/UX designs.
- Contributed approximately 50% to the development of our current project, which is a Next.js web-based application. This contribution includes key features, API routing, testing, auth integration and performance optimisations.
- Improved API efficiency by 20% by assisting backend developers in creating ~20 new routes.
- Implementation of backend functionality within these routes for database manipulation, altering data depending on the HTTP method passed through the route.
- Played a large part in the design of wireframes and mockups of our current project through Figma.

EXPERIENCE

06/2022 - Present

London

Frontend Engineer

ITV

- Taking part in the development of responsive and user-friendly web applications, ensuring a seamless user experience across these different applications working on ITVX Browser, ITVX Connected TV & the ITV News website.
- Collaborating with UX/UI designers to translate design mockups and wireframes into quality code.
- Being a lead developer and primary driving force for multiple projects that are currently live on ITVX. These include the Regional News functionality which went live onto ITVX December 2023. And the news/sport short form & category page. This work can be seen on the ITVX app on both connected TV and browser.
- Frequently contributing & maintaining the ITV News website which is interacted with by thousands on a monthly basis.
- Being a significant part of the ITV Hub to ITVX rebrand from start to finish.
- Optimise website performance through code and asset optimisation.

10/2020 - 06/2022

London

Software Development Engineer in Test

ITV

- Oversee the QA process for Account Management on the ITV Hub.
- Solely recreating an entire codebase, which contained all acceptance tests for video related
 features on the ITV Hub, from the ground up. This was due to the old codebase being very
 outdated. This codebase is now used on the daily by the video team to ensure all video related
 functionality works as expected.
- Contributing to, and maintaining, automated testing frameworks for ITV web & mobile applications, ensuring comprehensive coverage of functional and non-functional requirements.
- Develop and maintain automated test scripts using industry-standard tools and frameworks.
- Participate in code reviews, conduct root cause analysis for defects, and work collaboratively with developers to resolve issues and improve overall product quality.

09/2019 - 10/2020

London

05/2017 - 08/2018

Bracknell, Berkshire

07/2016 - 03/2017

Camberley, Surrey

10/2016 - 12/2016

Staines, Surrey

09/2015 - 01/2016

Birmingham

Technology Graduate

ITV

Data Analyst

IRi Worldwide

Assistant Manager & Pharmacy Advisor

Boots UK

Entertainments Performer

Merlin Entertainments

Bartender

The Green Man

EDUCATION

01/2018 - 01/2019

Kent

MSc Computer Science

University of Kent

01/2012 - 01/2016

Birmingham

B.Sc. Biological Sciences with a Year in Computer Science University of Birmingham

01/2005 - 01/2012

Camberley, Surrey

A-Levels - Maths (A*) Biology (A) Physics (A) Computing (A) GCSFs - 10 A*s - Bs

Collingwood College